<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regression on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/regression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regression on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 20:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/regression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>msaenet 3.1.2 and a sparse survival modeling example</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/msaenet-3-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/msaenet-3-1-2/</guid>
      <description>Father-Son Tennis. Photo by Lucas Davies. I’m pleased to announce that msaenet 3.1.2 is now available on CRAN.&#xA;You can install msaenet with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;msaenet&amp;quot;) If you frequently build sparse linear models, msaenet can help you generate more parsimonious solutions with adaptive estimations. It supports any number of adaptive estimation steps, flexible initialization methods, multiple model selection criteria, and automatic parallel parameter tuning.&#xA;New color palette This is a more focused update compared to the 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Index Tracking with msaenet and CVXR: A Two-Stage Regression Approach</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/sparse-index-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/sparse-index-tracking/</guid>
      <description>The code to reproduce the results in this post is also available here.&#xA;The illusion of choice. Photo by Kenny Eliason. Disclaimer The content in this blog post is for educational and research purposes only. It is not intended to be investment advice, and the author is not a licensed financial advisor. Any investment decisions should be based on your own analysis and consultation with a licensed financial advisor. The author is not responsible for any financial losses or damages resulting from the use of this information.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
