<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sparse linear models on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/sparse-linear-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sparse linear models on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/sparse-linear-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>R Package Release Notes: ggsci, protr, and msaenet (Spring 2024)</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-protr-msaenet-release-notes-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-protr-msaenet-release-notes-2024/</guid>
      <description>Cute market in Rome, Italy. Photo by Mark Pecar. Maintaining R packages is a significant time and effort commitment. The Releasing to CRAN chapter of the R Packages book provides an excellent overview of the many responsibilities package authors face. Henrik’s CRANhaven also helps me appreciate the efforts made by both CRAN maintainers and package maintainers to keep a consistent, high standard on software quality and integration within a single, trusted repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Index Tracking with msaenet and CVXR: A Two-Stage Regression Approach</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/sparse-index-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/sparse-index-tracking/</guid>
      <description>The code to reproduce the results in this post is also available here.&#xA;The illusion of choice. Photo by Kenny Eliason. Disclaimer The content in this blog post is for educational and research purposes only. It is not intended to be investment advice, and the author is not a licensed financial advisor. Any investment decisions should be based on your own analysis and consultation with a licensed financial advisor. The author is not responsible for any financial losses or damages resulting from the use of this information.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
