<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Markdown on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/r-markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Markdown on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/r-markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use STIX Fonts in R Markdown and Quarto for Readability</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</guid>
      <description>Seashore with Shipwreck by Moonlight by Caspar David Friedrich. I have been playing a lot of Elden Ring lately. After investing 200 (!) hours into it, I learned three valuable lessons:&#xA;Life is hard. Something that seems unachievable today doesn’t mean it will be tomorrow. Explore, learn, practice, and with efforts, and perhaps a little luck, suddenly, you’ve done it. Life is unfair. You can choose to play aggressively, play conservatively, or even move on—just don’t be greedy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the &#39;non-numeric argument to binary operator&#39; Error in R Markdown and Quarto</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/knitr-chunk-option-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/knitr-chunk-option-error/</guid>
      <description>Rubber duck debugging. Photo by Timothy Dykes. If Google leads you here, you probably assigned a character value to a knitr chunk option such as fig.width or fig.height that only accepts numeric values, and your are trying to render that R Markdown or Quarto document.&#xA;The exact error message you encountered looks like this:&#xA;Error in `options[[sprintf(&amp;quot;fig.%s&amp;quot;, i)]] * options$dpi`: ! non-numeric argument to binary operator Backtrace: 1. rmarkdown::render(&amp;quot;example.Rmd&amp;quot;, encoding = &amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;) 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressing PNG Output for R Packages with pngquant and ragg</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rpkgs-pngquant-ragg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rpkgs-pngquant-ragg/</guid>
      <description>Cassette collection. Photo by Jametlene Reskp. Introduction Dealing with large-scale image outputs in R packages can be challenging, especially when it comes to passing CRAN checks. In this post, I will share my experience in using pngquant and ragg to compress the PNG output size for readme and vignettes. This allows R packages with many figures in their documentation to pass the CRAN checks without compromising image quality.&#xA;Problem description I encountered a problem with my package, ggsci, which outputs approximately 30 example figures from both vignettes and README.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolden Your Typography in R Markdown and Quarto with MLModern</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</guid>
      <description>A visual comparison between Latin Modern (blue) and MLModern (red) at the same size. You probably have created PDF documents using R Markdown or Quarto. The default look and feel of these documents are driven by the default typeface, Computer Modern, or its extended implementation, Latin Modern.&#xA;To me, these default typefaces work fine, but they could be “thicker” to be more legible on HiDPI and Retina displays. MLModern offers such a sturdy rendition of the Computer Modern design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General-Purpose Link Checker for R Markdown and Quarto Projects</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rmarkdown-quarto-link-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rmarkdown-quarto-link-checker/</guid>
      <description>The link checker code in this post is also available in this GitHub Gist.&#xA;Puffins in the rain, Iceland. Photo by Yves Alarie.&#xA;Previously on link checking… We discussed the link rot issue before. We also built a simple link checker for blogdown projects based on the XML sitemap generated by Hugo. In reality, I maintain many more bookdown projects and Quarto projects than blogdown projects. Searching site: bookdown::bookdown_sitealso shows that there are 10,000+ bookdown projects hosted on GitHub alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Paginated News Lists in R Markdown and Shiny with DT</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/dt-news-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/dt-news-list/</guid>
      <description>The R code in this post is also available as this GitHub Gist.&#xA;Mosaic Mondrian. Original photo by Simon Lee.&#xA;Context and motivation A single-file R Markdown document often generates single-page HTML outputs. Similarly, Shiny is a single-page application framework. The single-page nature of these outputs makes it challenging to create experiences like pagination to display long and sophisticated lists, which is usually accomplished by creating multiple pages and URL routing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize Syntax Highlighting for R distill Websites</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/distill-syntax-highlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/distill-syntax-highlight/</guid>
      <description>“Diversity is essential to happiness, and in Utopia there is hardly any.” (Bertrand Russell) Photo by @chuttersnap.&#xA;The Problem The distill (formerly radix) package offers an excellent option in the R Markdown ecosystem to create beautifully typed websites. I was using it one day and looking into customizing the syntax highlighting theme. Then I found this issue:&#xA;I was a bit surprised and sad that there is no easy way to customize it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
