<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python packages on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/python-packages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python packages on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 02:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/python-packages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing py-ggsci: ggsci color palettes for plotnine in Python</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 02:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-python/</guid>
      <description>Cliff Walk at Pourville (1882) by Claude Monet: two women on a grassy cliff above the sea under a bright sky. Public domain. Source: Art Institute of Chicago. I’m thrilled to announce the release of py-ggsci, a Python package that brings the popular ggsci color palettes from R’s ggplot2 ecosystem to Python’s plotnine library.&#xA;You can install py-ggsci from PyPI:&#xA;pip install ggsci Here is a quick example using the Observable 10 palette introduced in ggsci 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing rtflite for Python</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rtflite-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rtflite-python/</guid>
      <description>Touring in the clouds. Photo by Clement Delhaye. This is a guest post generously contributed by Yilong Zhang, a biostatistician at Meta.&#xA;It is my pleasure to introduce rtflite, a new Python package for generating RTF documents. A preview version is now available on PyPI. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install rtflite The ultimate goal of rtflite is to provide a lightweight solution for generating production-ready tables, listings, and figures (TLFs) in RTF format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing pkglite for Python</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/pkglite-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/pkglite-python/</guid>
      <description>Les Menuires, France. Photo by Yann Allegre. I am pleased to introduce pkglite for Python, now available on PyPI. pkglite for Python provides a minimalist framework for packing source packages written in any programming language into a text file and restoring them to their original directory structure. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install pkglite For installation as a global command-line tool, use pipx:&#xA;pipx install pkglite Context Four years ago, we released the R package pkglite, designed for bidirectional conversion of R packages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tinyvdiff: Minimalist visual regression testing plugin for pytest</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinyvdiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinyvdiff/</guid>
      <description>Hummingbirds. Photo by Zdeněk Macháček. I’m delighted to announce my second Python package, tinyvdiff, now available on PyPI. It offers a lightweight pytest plugin for detecting appearance changes in visual content, such as figures or documents. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install tinyvdiff Setup and usage Here is an example test for matplotlib graphics, from the tinyvdiff demo project:&#xA;import pytest from tinyvdiff_demo.matplotlib import generate_plot @pytest.fixture def temp_pdf(tmp_path): &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Fixture to create a temporary PDF file path&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; return tmp_path / &amp;quot;test.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tinytopics: GPU-accelerated topic modeling via constrained neural Poisson NMF</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</guid>
      <description>Downhill mountain biking. Photo by Tim Foster. I’m excited to share that my first Python package, tinytopics, is now available on PyPI. You can install it using&#xA;pip install tinytopics tinytopics is a minimalist solution designed to scale up topic modeling tasks on CPUs and GPUs using PyTorch.&#xA;Motivation Fitting topic models at scale using classical algorithms on CPUs can be slow. Carbonetto et al. (2022) demonstrated the equivalence between Poisson non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) and multinomial topic model likelihoods.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
