<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarto on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/quarto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quarto on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/quarto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use STIX Fonts in R Markdown and Quarto for Readability</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</guid>
      <description>Seashore with Shipwreck by Moonlight by Caspar David Friedrich. I have been playing a lot of Elden Ring lately. After investing 200 (!) hours into it, I learned three valuable lessons:&#xA;Life is hard. Something that seems unachievable today doesn’t mean it will be tomorrow. Explore, learn, practice, and with efforts, and perhaps a little luck, suddenly, you’ve done it. Life is unfair. You can choose to play aggressively, play conservatively, or even move on—just don’t be greedy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the &#39;non-numeric argument to binary operator&#39; Error in R Markdown and Quarto</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/knitr-chunk-option-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/knitr-chunk-option-error/</guid>
      <description>Rubber duck debugging. Photo by Timothy Dykes. If Google leads you here, you probably assigned a character value to a knitr chunk option such as fig.width or fig.height that only accepts numeric values, and your are trying to render that R Markdown or Quarto document.&#xA;The exact error message you encountered looks like this:&#xA;Error in `options[[sprintf(&amp;quot;fig.%s&amp;quot;, i)]] * options$dpi`: ! non-numeric argument to binary operator Backtrace: 1. rmarkdown::render(&amp;quot;example.Rmd&amp;quot;, encoding = &amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;) 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Perfect Open Source Font: Introducing the Interactive Typeface Lookbook</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/open-source-typography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/open-source-typography/</guid>
      <description>Majesty Palm. Photo by Kara Eads. Introduction There are more than 1,500 open source font families available on Google Fonts, presenting designers and developers with an extensive, yet often overwhelming, array of options. With such a vast selection, it can be challenging to sift through and find the perfect typeface for your projects, let alone remember the hidden gems you may have come across in the past.&#xA;To address this challenge, I started Open Source Typography, an opinionated, curated lookbook of outstanding open source fonts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolden Your Typography in R Markdown and Quarto with MLModern</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</guid>
      <description>A visual comparison between Latin Modern (blue) and MLModern (red) at the same size. You probably have created PDF documents using R Markdown or Quarto. The default look and feel of these documents are driven by the default typeface, Computer Modern, or its extended implementation, Latin Modern.&#xA;To me, these default typefaces work fine, but they could be “thicker” to be more legible on HiDPI and Retina displays. MLModern offers such a sturdy rendition of the Computer Modern design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General-Purpose Link Checker for R Markdown and Quarto Projects</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rmarkdown-quarto-link-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rmarkdown-quarto-link-checker/</guid>
      <description>The link checker code in this post is also available in this GitHub Gist.&#xA;Puffins in the rain, Iceland. Photo by Yves Alarie.&#xA;Previously on link checking… We discussed the link rot issue before. We also built a simple link checker for blogdown projects based on the XML sitemap generated by Hugo. In reality, I maintain many more bookdown projects and Quarto projects than blogdown projects. Searching site: bookdown::bookdown_sitealso shows that there are 10,000+ bookdown projects hosted on GitHub alone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
