<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>revdepcheck on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/revdepcheck/</link>
    <description>Recent content in revdepcheck on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/revdepcheck/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>revdeprun: Rust CLI for R package reverse dependency check automation</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/revdeprun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/revdeprun/</guid>
      <description>Smoke and speed: a race car mid-drift on the track. Photo by Jack Stapleton. Update (2025-10-31): revdeprun 1.0.0 switched to using a custom workflow to pre-install binary dependencies for checking reverse dependencies, and run parallel checks using xfun::rev_check(). This improvement significantly improves performance and reliability. Read the release notes here. This post has been updated to reflect these changes.&#xA;I’m glad to announce the release of revdeprun, a Rust CLI tool that makes it easy to run reverse dependency checks on cloud instances1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ggsci 3.1.0, ggsurvfit example, and reverse dependency check</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Elena Mozhvilo. I am excited to announce the release of ggsci 3.1.0. ggsci is an R package that provides a collection of color palettes inspired by colors used in scientific journals, data visualization libraries, science fiction movies, and TV shows.&#xA;To install ggsci from CRAN, run:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;ggsci&amp;quot;) This release introduces a new color scale and brings documentation improvements. This post demonstrates how to create a Kaplan-Meier plot using ggsurvfit, cowplot, and ggsci.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
