<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readability on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/readability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readability on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 23:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/readability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DM Mono with Fira Code ligatures</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/dm-mono-ligaturized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 23:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/dm-mono-ligaturized/</guid>
      <description>I’ve created a ligaturized version of DM Mono by adding Fira Code ligatures. You can download it from GitHub: https://github.com/nanxstats/dm-mono-ligaturized.&#xA;Ligaturized DM Mono in action: Running Homebrew in Ghostty. Theme: Dracula+. Why ligatures? I’ll confess: I can’t start real work until I’ve found a coding font that fits the vibe of the day. My dotfiles are fairly basic, but they include an extensive list of free and commercial monospaced fonts that I rotate through regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Inter with alternative optical sizing presets</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</guid>
      <description>A cylinder casting a circular and rectangular shadow on two perpendicular planes, showing how perspective shapes interpretation of a single form. 3D render by Daniels Joffe. Since its open source release in 2017, Inter has become a widely adopted sans-serif font, especially popular for web content and user interfaces that benefit from a clean, neo-grotesque style. Thoughtful glyph redesigns in versions 4.0 and 4.1 (released since 2023) have further enhanced its technical maturity and visual appeal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You should (maybe) enable font ligatures when building with GPT models</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gpt-models-font-ligatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gpt-models-font-ligatures/</guid>
      <description>Parts of a typewriter. Photo by Florian Klauer. The token &amp;lt;|endoftext|&amp;gt; is a special token used as a document separator for OpenAI GPT models. It has become quite prevalent if you look closely:&#xA;It has been used since GPT-2 and remains present in the OpenAI API for their latest models. Their tokenizer package, tiktoken, includes logic to process text with these special tokens. The markup &amp;lt;| and |&amp;gt; is widely used in the code bases of LangChain and text-generation-webui.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use STIX Fonts in R Markdown and Quarto for Readability</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/stixfonts/</guid>
      <description>Seashore with Shipwreck by Moonlight by Caspar David Friedrich. I have been playing a lot of Elden Ring lately. After investing 200 (!) hours into it, I learned three valuable lessons:&#xA;Life is hard. Something that seems unachievable today doesn’t mean it will be tomorrow. Explore, learn, practice, and with efforts, and perhaps a little luck, suddenly, you’ve done it. Life is unfair. You can choose to play aggressively, play conservatively, or even move on—just don’t be greedy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolden Your Typography in R Markdown and Quarto with MLModern</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/mlmodern/</guid>
      <description>A visual comparison between Latin Modern (blue) and MLModern (red) at the same size. You probably have created PDF documents using R Markdown or Quarto. The default look and feel of these documents are driven by the default typeface, Computer Modern, or its extended implementation, Latin Modern.&#xA;To me, these default typefaces work fine, but they could be “thicker” to be more legible on HiDPI and Retina displays. MLModern offers such a sturdy rendition of the Computer Modern design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Human-Readable Text Data with Readability.js and R</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-readability-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-readability-parser/</guid>
      <description>The R and JavaScript code to reproduce the results in this post is available from https://github.com/nanxstats/r-readability-parser.&#xA;Photo by Nick Hillier. Update (2023-09-04): Browserify support was removed in jsdom v22.0.0. This post has been updated to recommend installing jsdom v20.0.0 to ensure the code examples work as intended. The original versions of JS libraries in the GitHub repo remain unchanged, as they continue to function correctly.&#xA;Readability.js Maybe you have used tools like rvest to harvest text data from web pages.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
