<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot2 on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot2 on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Design for Statistical Graphics with Shiny and ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/responsive-design-for-statistical-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/responsive-design-for-statistical-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Amy Shamblen. If you have written any Shiny apps, you are probably familiar with the idea of responsive web design, which focuses on web page layouts adaptive to screen size and popularized by the front-end frameworks such as Bootstrap.
Could the similar idea be applied to statistical graphics? In my opinion, the answer is yes, and the idea can be helpful for arranging multi-panel graphics under the context of creating effective visualizations that are adaptive to any screen sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggsci 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-0-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-0-0/</guid>
      <description>3D render from Rodion Kutsaiev. I am delighted to announce the release of ggsci 3.0.0. ggsci provides a collection of color palettes inspired by colors used in scientific journals, data visualization libraries, science fiction movies, and TV shows.
You can install it from CRAN with:
install.packages(&amp;quot;ggsci&amp;quot;) This version brings 7 new color palettes under 3 color scales (COSMIC, Flat UI, Frontiers), multiple improvements, and a new FAQ vignette, giving you more options to create effective data visualizations using ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive ggplot2 Color Scales with Color Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggplot2-color-interpolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggplot2-color-interpolation/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Mateo Giraud.
My R package ggsci has included a few popular discrete color palettes. The colors values in these palettes are not automatically generated from a color space but hand-picked instead, often containing only five to ten distinct colors. A frequent question from the users is: What should I do when the colors are running out due to a more significant number of categories in the data?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
