<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GPU on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/gpu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GPU on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/gpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring the GPU Selector App with Claude Code: A Vibe Coding Experiment</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/claude-code-vibe-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/claude-code-vibe-refactor/</guid>
      <description>Desk setup with plants. Photo by Amari James. In January 2023, I built a basic, interactive deep learning GPU selector app inspired by Tim Dettmers’ popular guide. The original project was a pure HTML + JavaScript + CSS “vibe coding” experiment, driven by chat with GPT-3.5, which was the SOTA at the time. While the core logic worked, I did not focus much on its UI or UX.&#xA;Now, two and a half years later, I wanted to see how far agentic coding assistants have come, by refactoring the app with modern tools and design sensibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First PyCon Experience</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/my-first-pycon-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/my-first-pycon-experience/</guid>
      <description>A flamingo peeking through the plants. National Aviary, Pittsburgh, PA. Photo by Adam Custer. I attended PyCon US 2025 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania from May 16–18, 2025. As my first Python conference, I wanted to document the most interesting things I learned.&#xA;Why a statistician goes to PyCon? It might seem odd for a statistician to focus on any particular programming language. But I’m not your typical statistician. As Dijkstra said:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tinytopics: GPU-accelerated topic modeling via constrained neural Poisson NMF</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</guid>
      <description>Downhill mountain biking. Photo by Tim Foster. I’m excited to share that my first Python package, tinytopics, is now available on PyPI. You can install it using&#xA;pip install tinytopics tinytopics is a minimalist solution designed to scale up topic modeling tasks on CPUs and GPUs using PyTorch.&#xA;Motivation Fitting topic models at scale using classical algorithms on CPUs can be slow. Carbonetto et al. (2022) demonstrated the equivalence between Poisson non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) and multinomial topic model likelihoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning GPU Selector</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gpu-selector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gpu-selector/</guid>
      <description>I built a GPU selector for deep learning workflows at nanx.me/gpu/, based on the recommendations from the blog post written by Tim Dettmers.&#xA;You can use this tool to decide the GPU you need for general training or inference needs by answering a few yes/no questions. It was a simple, pure client-side JavaScript implementation (GitHub repo).&#xA;AI and sustainability. Artwork from DeepMind. Artist: Nidia Dias. I first saw Tim’s post when the Ampere series was released in 2020.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
