<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clinical trials on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/clinical-trials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in clinical trials on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/clinical-trials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing rtflite for Python</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rtflite-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rtflite-python/</guid>
      <description>Touring in the clouds. Photo by Clement Delhaye. This is a guest post generously contributed by Yilong Zhang, a biostatistician at Meta.&#xA;It is my pleasure to introduce rtflite, a new Python package for generating RTF documents. A preview version is now available on PyPI. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install rtflite The ultimate goal of rtflite is to provide a lightweight solution for generating production-ready tables, listings, and figures (TLFs) in RTF format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing pkglite for Python</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/pkglite-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/pkglite-python/</guid>
      <description>Les Menuires, France. Photo by Yann Allegre. I am pleased to introduce pkglite for Python, now available on PyPI. pkglite for Python provides a minimalist framework for packing source packages written in any programming language into a text file and restoring them to their original directory structure. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install pkglite For installation as a global command-line tool, use pipx:&#xA;pipx install pkglite Context Four years ago, we released the R package pkglite, designed for bidirectional conversion of R packages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group sequential trials in industry: a 30-year perspective</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/group-sequential-trials-industry-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/group-sequential-trials-industry-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Estée Janssens. I’m delighted to share that our paper, Some Group Sequential Trials From Industry Over the Last 30 Years, has been published in Statistics in Biopharmaceutical Research. You can download the accepted manuscript (PDF, 457 KB) here.&#xA;Key takeaways The paper began as a conference talk presented by Keaven, our lead author, in 2022. Recognizing the value of these stories, we decided to develop them into a full-length paper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Questions About Adaptive Design</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/nine-questions-about-adaptive-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/nine-questions-about-adaptive-design/</guid>
      <description>Muir Woods trails. Photo by Caleb Jones. For someone who has worked in the industry for years, one thing I miss about school is the Socratic method of teaching used by some professors. It involves asking and answering questions to encourage critical thinking. By engaging in thoughtful Q&amp;amp;A sessions, I often find myself understanding the core elements of complex topics better compared to reading textbooks or papers alone.&#xA;To me, adaptive clinical trial design is one of these complex topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Paper Published: eCTD Submission with Analysis Using R</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ectd-pkglite-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ectd-pkglite-paper/</guid>
      <description>Photo by DeepMind.&#xA;I am thrilled to share that our paper, Electronic Common Technical Document Submission with Analysis Using R, is published online today in Clinical Trials. We have selected the open access (OA) option to ensure that everyone in the community can check out the full text freely.&#xA;A simple solution to a complex problem Our article presented a viable path to prepare proprietary R assets for submission, following the electronic common technical document (eCTD) specification.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
