<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>css on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/css/</link>
    <description>Recent content in css on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/css/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Inter with alternative optical sizing presets</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</guid>
      <description>A cylinder casting a circular and rectangular shadow on two perpendicular planes, showing how perspective shapes interpretation of a single form. 3D render by Daniels Joffe. Since its open source release in 2017, Inter has become a widely adopted sans-serif font, especially popular for web content and user interfaces that benefit from a clean, neo-grotesque style. Thoughtful glyph redesigns in versions 4.0 and 4.1 (released since 2023) have further enhanced its technical maturity and visual appeal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Font Variant Numeric</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/font-variant-numeric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/font-variant-numeric/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: If you use the native font stack (the default in Bootstrap 4+), check the numbers displayed in tables, especially on Apple’s platforms.&#xA;Photo by Jen Theodore.&#xA;A new problem Many of the content creation frameworks that support HTML output in the R world are getting upgraded to Bootstrap 4+:&#xA;Shiny and R Markdown can use bslib to customize Bootstrap version; The three-column Bootstrap style for bookdown projects; The pkgdown 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Return of the Native Font Stack</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/the-return-of-the-native-font-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/the-return-of-the-native-font-stack/</guid>
      <description>Photo: Lead type&#xA;As people said, web design is 95% typography. Once upon a time, people who care about the typography of their website define their font stack using CSS like this:&#xA;font-family: &amp;quot;Lucida Sans Unicode&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Lucida Grande&amp;quot;, sans-serif; They secretly wish their website could look different from the mortal websites which use Times New Roman, Arial, or Georgia with the funny-looking numerals.&#xA;Until one day, their sincerity impressed the god of typography, who granted them a technology named web fonts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
