<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data visualization on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data visualization on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ggsci 3.2.0: new color palettes from Observable, Bootstrap, and Tailwind CSS</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Villa in Zurich, perspective view. From “Moderne Architektur” (Modern Architecture), edited by Lambert &amp;amp; Stahl, Stuttgart, 1891. Scan from Europeana. I am delighted to announce the release of ggsci 3.2.0. The R package ggsci was first released in 2016. It offers a range of ggplot2 color scales drawn from various sources, including scientific publications, data visualization tools, sci-fi movies, and television series.&#xA;To install ggsci from CRAN, use:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;ggsci&amp;quot;) As a follow-up to the ggsci 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ggsci 3.1.0, ggsurvfit example, and reverse dependency check</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ggsci-3-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Elena Mozhvilo. I am excited to announce the release of ggsci 3.1.0. ggsci is an R package that provides a collection of color palettes inspired by colors used in scientific journals, data visualization libraries, science fiction movies, and TV shows.&#xA;To install ggsci from CRAN, run:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;ggsci&amp;quot;) This release introduces a new color scale and brings documentation improvements. This post demonstrates how to create a Kaplan-Meier plot using ggsurvfit, cowplot, and ggsci.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create Engaging Word Cloud Visualizations from Your Research</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Many outstanding researchers and labs have created visualizations of their research using word clouds. In this post, I present a simple, automated “paper2wordcloud” workflow to create eye-catching word cloud visualizations. It combines the efficiency of automation with the power of human intuition and aesthetic sense. The figure below was created using my published papers.&#xA;A word cloud visualization generated for my papers using this workflow. The general steps in the workflow are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Word Cloud Generator</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rethinking-word-cloud-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rethinking-word-cloud-generator/</guid>
      <description>As part of my JavaScript learning journey, I created a fork of Jason Davies’ word cloud generator and added some new features with a few adjustments to the default parameters. The fork is hosted at nanx.me/wordcloud/ and the source code is available on GitHub. Here is an example word cloud produced by the generator:&#xA;A word cloud visualization for ChatGPT release notes produced by the generator with default parameters. Font: Founders Grotesk Condensed Regular (included with macOS).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
