<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Engaging Word Cloud Visualizations from Your Research</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Many outstanding researchers and labs have created visualizations of their research using word clouds. In this post, I present a simple, automated “paper2wordcloud” workflow to create eye-catching word cloud visualizations. It combines the efficiency of automation with the power of human intuition and aesthetic sense. The figure below was created using my published papers.
A word cloud visualization generated for my papers using this workflow. The general steps in the workflow are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Past and Future of Shiny Keynote at rstudio::conf(2022)</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/shiny-keynote-rstudio-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/shiny-keynote-rstudio-conf/</guid>
      <description>I constantly feel lucky to witness the growth of the R web framework, Shiny, in the past ten years. In his keynote speech at rstudio::conf 2022, Joe Cheng shared an excellent summary of Shiny’s achievements and exciting outlook.
I am deeply moved by the story about how Shiny was created and Joe’s journey, and I recommend you watch the talk recording below if you haven’t. Notably, after Hadley’s Mastering Shiny book, the community-maintained awesome list awesome-shiny-extensions was again highlighted in Joe’s talk from 24:00 to 24:33 (thanks so much for the shout-out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
