<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>tinyvdiff: Minimalist visual regression testing plugin for pytest</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinyvdiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinyvdiff/</guid>
      <description>Hummingbirds. Photo by Zdeněk Macháček. I’m delighted to announce my second Python package, tinyvdiff, now available on PyPI. It offers a lightweight pytest plugin for detecting appearance changes in visual content, such as figures or documents. You can install it with:&#xA;pip install tinyvdiff Setup and usage Here is an example test for matplotlib graphics, from the tinyvdiff demo project:&#xA;import pytest from tinyvdiff_demo.matplotlib import generate_plot @pytest.fixture def temp_pdf(tmp_path): &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Fixture to create a temporary PDF file path&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; return tmp_path / &amp;quot;test.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tinytopics: GPU-accelerated topic modeling via constrained neural Poisson NMF</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/tinytopics/</guid>
      <description>Downhill mountain biking. Photo by Tim Foster. I’m excited to share that my first Python package, tinytopics, is now available on PyPI. You can install it using&#xA;pip3 install tinytopics tinytopics is a minimalist solution designed to scale up topic modeling tasks on CPUs and GPUs using PyTorch.&#xA;Motivation Fitting topic models at scale using classical algorithms on CPUs can be slow. Carbonetto et al. (2022) demonstrated the equivalence between Poisson non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) and multinomial topic model likelihoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create Engaging Word Cloud Visualizations from Your Research</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/research-word-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Many outstanding researchers and labs have created visualizations of their research using word clouds. In this post, I present a simple, automated “paper2wordcloud” workflow to create eye-catching word cloud visualizations. It combines the efficiency of automation with the power of human intuition and aesthetic sense. The figure below was created using my published papers.&#xA;A word cloud visualization generated for my papers using this workflow. The general steps in the workflow are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Past and Future of Shiny Keynote at rstudio::conf(2022)</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/shiny-keynote-rstudio-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/shiny-keynote-rstudio-conf/</guid>
      <description>I constantly feel lucky to witness the growth of the R web framework, Shiny, in the past ten years. In his keynote speech at rstudio::conf 2022, Joe Cheng shared an excellent summary of Shiny’s achievements and exciting outlook.&#xA;I am deeply moved by the story about how Shiny was created and Joe’s journey, and I recommend you watch the talk recording below if you haven’t. Notably, after Hadley’s Mastering Shiny book, the community-maintained awesome list awesome-shiny-extensions was again highlighted in Joe’s talk from 24:00 to 24:33 (thanks so much for the shout-out!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
