<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanka on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/tanka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tanka on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/tanka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tanka: A Minimalist Bootstrap 4 Theme for Hugo and Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/hugo-tanka-theme-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/hugo-tanka-theme-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: I have rewritten the Hugo Tanka theme entirely using Bootstrap 4 while still keeping its original look and feel. This should also fix the compatibility issues from Hugo version updates.
A screenshot of the updated Hugo Tanka theme.
Almost three years ago, when I first started blogging with Hugo/blogdown, I forked and modified a Hugo theme Black &amp;amp; Light, and named it Tanka (Repo, Live Preview).
Hugo has received several major updates in the past three years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanka: A Minimalist Theme for Hugo and Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/hugo-tanka-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/hugo-tanka-theme/</guid>
      <description>I used to mention creating a purely R-based static website generator named Haiku with my then classmate Arjun about two years ago. I remember that he said the name was nice.
Time flies, and apparently, I did not have the chance to build it. Fortunately, Yihui saved the world again, and now blogdown has become the most elegant and powerful static website generator for R users, especially if you love R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
