<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automatic differentiation on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/automatic-differentiation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automatic differentiation on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/automatic-differentiation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Lasso with greta</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/bayesian-lasso-with-greta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/bayesian-lasso-with-greta/</guid>
      <description>The R code to reproduce the results is available from GitHub Gist.
Horseshoe Bend, Arizona. Photo by Madeline Pere.
Although I am not an expert in Bayesian statistics, I always have an idealized version of the framework for Bayesian modeling in my mind:
Allows defining data models intuitively — preferably in native R. Handles the low-level computations such as MCMC automatically. Works on both CPU and GPU seamlessly would be perfect for 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Regularized Logistic Regressions from Scratch with Computational Graphs in R</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/cgraph-logreg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/cgraph-logreg/</guid>
      <description>The R package built for this post is available on GitHub: nanxstats/logreg.
Update 2020-02-11: there has been some major API updates and improvements since cgraph 5.0.0. The logreg package is now updated to reflect these changes. The code example in this post is updated, too.
As one of the cornerstones for deep learning frameworks, automatic differentiation was briefly mentioned in our previous post. Today let’s focus on the other important piece: the computational graph.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
