<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaScript on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaScript on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring the GPU Selector App with Claude Code: A Vibe Coding Experiment</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/claude-code-vibe-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/claude-code-vibe-refactor/</guid>
      <description>Desk setup with plants. Photo by Amari James. In January 2023, I built a basic, interactive deep learning GPU selector app inspired by Tim Dettmers’ popular guide. The original project was a pure HTML + JavaScript + CSS “vibe coding” experiment, driven by chat with GPT-3.5, which was the SOTA at the time. While the core logic worked, I did not focus much on its UI or UX.&#xA;Now, two and a half years later, I wanted to see how far agentic coding assistants have come, by refactoring the app with modern tools and design sensibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Inter with alternative optical sizing presets</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/inter-optical-sizing/</guid>
      <description>A cylinder casting a circular and rectangular shadow on two perpendicular planes, showing how perspective shapes interpretation of a single form. 3D render by Daniels Joffe. Since its open source release in 2017, Inter has become a widely adopted sans-serif font, especially popular for web content and user interfaces that benefit from a clean, neo-grotesque style. Thoughtful glyph redesigns in versions 4.0 and 4.1 (released since 2023) have further enhanced its technical maturity and visual appeal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI Automation with RobotJS</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gui-automation-robotjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/gui-automation-robotjs/</guid>
      <description>The code in this post is also available in this GitHub Gist.&#xA;Disclaimer: the tools and configurations mentioned in this post are only discussed as technical examples; they do not constitute an endorsement. Use at your own risk.&#xA;Photo by Martin Reisch. Today’s internet is not like it was 20 years ago for an older millennial like me. Only judging by its appearance, the internet today is plagued with cookie consent popups and paywalls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Human-Readable Text Data with Readability.js and R</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-readability-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-readability-parser/</guid>
      <description>The R and JavaScript code to reproduce the results in this post is available from https://github.com/nanxstats/r-readability-parser.&#xA;Photo by Nick Hillier. Update (2023-09-04): Browserify support was removed in jsdom v22.0.0. This post has been updated to recommend installing jsdom v20.0.0 to ensure the code examples work as intended. The original versions of JS libraries in the GitHub repo remain unchanged, as they continue to function correctly.&#xA;Readability.js Maybe you have used tools like rvest to harvest text data from web pages.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
