<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R packages on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</title>
    <link>https://nanx.me/tags/r-packages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R packages on Nan Xiao | 肖楠</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nanx.me/tags/r-packages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>protr 1.7-0</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/protr-1-7-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/protr-1-7-0/</guid>
      <description>3D render from Google DeepMind. Artist: Wes Cockx. I am glad to announce the release of protr 1.7-0. Install it from CRAN with:&#xA;install.packages(&amp;quot;protr&amp;quot;) You can also install it from conda-forge in Python.&#xA;First released in 2012, protr was my very first open source R package. The package generates representations for protein sequences such as numerical features and similarity measures. Since its inception, protr has evolved after 21 CRAN releases by incorporating user feedback.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-Free R Package Release Checklist Generation with usethis</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-package-release-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/r-package-release-checklist/</guid>
      <description>The release checklist generation function described in this post is also available in this GitHub Gist.&#xA;Photo by David Marcu. Software release at scale An agile, automated, and reliable release process is a key component of continuous delivery for modern software engineering teams. In particular, releasing new versions of R packages often involves going through a sequence of manual and automated checks to ensure quality and compliance. To scale up such efforts within a development team, it is crucial to follow a consistent release checklist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressing PNG Output for R Packages with pngquant and ragg</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rpkgs-pngquant-ragg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rpkgs-pngquant-ragg/</guid>
      <description>Cassette collection. Photo by Jametlene Reskp. Introduction Dealing with large-scale image outputs in R packages can be challenging, especially when it comes to passing CRAN checks. In this post, I will share my experience in using pngquant and ragg to compress the PNG output size for readme and vignettes. This allows R packages with many figures in their documentation to pass the CRAN checks without compromising image quality.&#xA;Problem description I encountered a problem with my package, ggsci, which outputs approximately 30 example figures from both vignettes and README.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Paper Published: eCTD Submission with Analysis Using R</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ectd-pkglite-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/ectd-pkglite-paper/</guid>
      <description>Photo by DeepMind.&#xA;I am thrilled to share that our paper, Electronic Common Technical Document Submission with Analysis Using R, is published online today in Clinical Trials. We have selected the open access (OA) option to ensure that everyone in the community can check out the full text freely.&#xA;A simple solution to a complex problem Our article presented a viable path to prepare proprietary R assets for submission, following the electronic common technical document (eCTD) specification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Than 1,500 File Extensions Are Used Inside R Packages</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/cran-file-exts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/cran-file-exts/</guid>
      <description>The R code to reproduce the results is available from the GitHub repo nanxstats/cran-file-exts.&#xA;Photo by Pawel Czerwinski. When applied correctly, file extensions can be informative. They are the very first clue on handling a specific file without parsing the file content.&#xA;To properly capture and classify files in source R packages, I am interested in learning what file extensions are frequently used by R packages.&#xA;We can achieve this easily by downloading all R packages available from CRAN one at a time and collect the file extensions inside:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebranding R Packages with Hexagon Stickers: A Minimalist Approach</title>
      <link>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rebranding-r-packages-with-hexagon-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanx.me/blog/post/rebranding-r-packages-with-hexagon-stickers/</guid>
      <description>A new hex sticker wall of my R packages. I have built a few R packages over the years. I have always been adding some forms of an ad hoc logo to them, trying to make a visual impression. As the portfolio size grows larger, I realized that I would need a principled way to create the logos and refresh my packages’ look. Hexagon stickers seem to be an acceptable form of logos that are heavily used by the R community.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
